<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GymDroid</string>
    <string name="disc_fencing">Fencing</string>
    <string name="disc_fire">Firelighting</string>
    <string name="disc_gaming">Serious Gaming</string>
    <string name="disc_racing">Racing</string>
    <string name="disc_reading">Reading</string>
    <string name="disc_relay_race">Relay Race</string>
    <string name="disc_shooting">Shooting</string>
    <string name="disc_speed_running">Running</string>
    <string name="disc_typing">Fast Typing</string>
    <string name="disc_walking">Walking</string>

    <string name="disc_fencing_desc">Contemporary fencing is the word used for modern sport fencing which is very different from the martial use of the sword (also known as western art of combat with the small sword); Sport fencing is also called Olympic fencing which began in the end of the 19th century, with the Italian school having modified the "classical fencing", and the French school having later refined the Italian system. Modern fencing uses three weapons, and so is divided respectively into three competitive scenes: foil, sabre (spelt "saber" in the United States) and épée. Most (but not all) competitive fencers choose to specialise in one of these only. Competitive fencing is one of five activities which have been featured in every one of the modern Olympic Games, the other four being Athletics, Cycling, Swimming, and Gymnastics.</string>
    <string name="disc_fire_desc">Fire making, fire lighting or fire craft is the process of starting a fire artificially. Fire was an essential tool in early human cultural development.[1] It requires completing the fire triangle, usually by initiating the combustion of a suitably flammable material. The control of fire by early humans probably dates back to Homo erectus or very early Homo sapiens: that is, 400-200 thousand years ago based on archaeological evidence of hearths.[2] Changes in physique suggest it could back 1.8 or even 2.3 million years, the latter of which would date to Homo Habilis.[3] Smouldering plants and trees, or any source of hot coals from natural fires, may have been the first resources exploited by humans to control fire. Friction is the most commonly used primitive method for making fire. Ancient techniques for starting friction fires include the hand drill, the bow drill, the fire plow and the pump drill. Another ancient technique is the flint and steel method, where hot sparks are struck from a piece of steel or iron onto suitable tinder, such as tinder fungus or char-cloth, and fanned into flames. These methods have been known since the Paleolithic age, and are still in common use by some indigenous peoples. The skills required to create, control and use fire using primitive methods, often in a survival situation, have come into popular use as a component of bushcraft.</string>
    <string name="disc_gaming_desc">eSports (also known as eSport, esports, esport, e-sports, competitive (video) gaming, electronic sports, professional (video) gaming or pro-gaming) can be defined as a form of sports where the primary aspects of the sport are facilitated by video games; the input of players and teams as well as the output of the eSports system are mediated by human-computer interfaces.[1] Most commonly eSports take the form of organized multiplayer video game competitions, particularly between professional players. The most common video game genres associated with esports are real-time strategy, fighting, first-person shooter (FPS), and multiplayer online battle arena (MOBA). Tournaments such as The International, the League of Legends World Championship, the Battle.net World Championship Series, the Evolution Championship Series, and the Intel Extreme Masters, provide both live broadcasts of the competition, and prize money and salaries to competitors.</string>
    <string name="disc_racing_desc">In sport, racing is a competition of speed, against an objective criterion, usually a clock or to a specific point. The competitors in a race try to complete a given task in the shortest amount of time. Typically this involves traversing some distance, but it can be any other task involving speed to reach a specific goal. A race may be run continuously from start to finish or may be made of several segments called heats, stages or legs. A heat is usually run over the same course at different times. A stage is a shorter section of a much longer course or a time trial. Early records of races are evident on pottery from ancient Greece, which depicted running men vying for first place. A chariot race is described in Homer s Iliad.</string>
    <string name="disc_reading_desc">Reading is a complex cognitive process of decoding symbols in order to construct or derive meaning (reading comprehension). It is a means of language acquisition, of communication, and of sharing information and ideas. Like all languages, it is a complex interaction between the text and the reader which is shaped by the reader’s prior knowledge, experiences, attitude, and language community which is culturally and socially situated. The reading process requires continuous practice, development, and refinement. In addition, reading requires creativity and critical analysis. Consumers of literature make ventures with each piece, innately deviating from literal words to create images that make sense to them in the unfamiliar places the texts describe. Because reading is such a complex process, it cannot be controlled or restricted to one or two interpretations. There are no concrete laws in reading, but rather allows readers an escape to produce their own products introspectively. This promotes deep exploration of texts during interpretation.[1] Readers use a variety of reading strategies to assist with decoding (to translate symbols into sounds or visual representations of speech) and comprehension. Readers may use context clues to identify the meaning of unknown words. Readers integrate the words they have read into their existing framework of knowledge or schema (schemata theory).</string>
    <string name="disc_relay_race_desc">During a relay race, members of a team take turns running, orienteering, swimming, cross-country skiing, biathlon, or ice skating (usually with a baton in the fist) parts of a circuit or performing a certain action. Relay races take the form of professional races and amateur games. In the Olympic games, there are several types of relay races that are part of track and field.</string>
    <string name="disc_shooting_desc">A shooting sport is a competitive sport involving tests of proficiency (accuracy and speed) using various types of guns such as firearms and airguns. Hunting is also a shooting sport, and indeed shooting live pheasants was an Olympic event (albeit only once, in 1900).[citation needed] The shooting sports are categorized by the type of firearm, targets, and distances at which the targets are shot.</string>
    <string name="disc_speed_running_desc">Sprinting is the act of running over a short distance at (or near) top speed. It is used in many sports that incorporate running, typically as a way of quickly reaching a target or goal, or avoiding or catching an opponent. Human physiology dictates that a runner s near-top speed cannot be maintained for more than 30–35 seconds due to the depletion of Phosphocreatine stores in muscles, and perhaps secondarily to excessive Metabolic acidosis as a result of Anaerobic glycolysis.[1] In athletics and track and field, sprints (or dashes) are races over short distances. They are among the oldest running competitions. The first 13 editions of the Ancient Olympic Games featured only one event—the stadion race, which was a race from one end of the stadium to the other.[2] There are three sprinting events which are currently held at the Summer Olympics and outdoor World Championships: the 100 metres, 200 metres, and 400 metres. These events have their roots in races of imperial measurements which were later altered to metric: the 100 m evolved from the 100 yard dash,[3] the 200 m distances came from the furlong (or 1/8 of a mile),[4] and the 400 m was the successor to the 440 yard dash or quarter-mile race.[1]</string>
    <string name="disc_typing_desc">Typing is the process of writing or inputting text by pressing keys on a typewriter, computer keyboard, cell phone, or calculator. It can be distinguished from other means of text input, such as handwriting and speech recognition. Text can be in the form of letters, numbers and other symbols. The world s first typist was Lillian Sholes from Wisconsin.[1][2] She was the daughter of Christopher Sholes, the man who invented the first practical typewriter.[1] User interface features such as spell checker and autocomplete serve to facilitate and speed up typing and to prevent or correct errors the typist may make.</string>
    <string name="disc_walking_desc">Racewalking, or race walking, is a long-distance discipline within the sport of athletics. Although it is a foot race, it is different from running in that one foot must appear to be in contact with the ground at all times. This is assessed by race judges, making it the most subjective of the disciplines in athletics. Typically held on either roads or on running tracks, common distances vary from 3000 metres (1.8 mi) up to 100 kilometres (62.1 mi). There are two racewalking distances contested at the Summer Olympics: the 20 kilometres race walk (men and women) and 50 kilometres race walk (men only). Both are held as road events. The biennial IAAF World Championships in Athletics also features the same three events. The IAAF World Race Walking Cup, first held in 1961, is a stand-alone global competition for the discipline and it has 10 kilometres race walks for junior athletes, in addition to the Olympic-standard events. The IAAF World Indoor Championships featured 5000 m and 3000 m race walk variations, but these were discontinued after 1993. Top level athletics championships and games typically feature 20 km racewalking events.</string>

    <string name="schedule_1">Mon &amp; Thu 1-2</string>
    <string name="schedule_2">Tue &amp; Fri 2-3</string>
    <string name="schedule_3">Wed &amp; Fri 4-5</string>
    <string name="schedule_4">Mon &amp; Wed 3-4</string>
    <string name="action_share_discipline">Share</string>
    <string name="action_search_discipline">Search Discipline</string>

</resources>